[Wei]
[وي]
It's not too late to regret now.
لم يفت الأوان للندم الآن.
Come with me instead.
تعال معي بدلا من ذلك.
Go with you?
اذهب معك؟
To do what?
لفعل ماذا؟
Rob and murder or swindle and plunder?
السرقة والقتل أم الاحتيال والنهب؟
Bully the weak or harass women?
التنمر على الضعفاء أو التحرش بالنساء؟
Should I be like you every day,
هل يجب أن أكون مثلك كل يوم،
doing shady things,
القيام بأشياء مشبوهة،
living like a rat in the gutter,
العيش مثل الفأر في الحضيض،
despised and hated by everyone?
محتقر ومكروه من الجميع؟
I never knew you were such a talker.
لم أكن أعلم أنك تتحدث بهذه الطريقة.
Talked yourself hoarse, haven't you?
لقد تحدثت عن نفسك بصوت أجش، أليس كذلك؟
[Li Ling]
[لي لينغ]
You slept with my woman,
لقد نمت مع امرأتي،
and you still have the nerve to act righteous.
ولا زال لديك الشجاعة للتصرف بشكل صحيح.
Su Changming, let me tell you,
سو تشانغ مينغ، اسمح لي أن أخبرك،
from today on,
من اليوم فصاعدا،
I have nothing to do with your Guantian Society.
ليس لي أي علاقة بجمعية غوانتيان الخاصة بك.
Whatever you want,
أياً كان ما تريد،
get it yourself with your own abilities.
احصل عليه بنفسك بقدراتك الخاصة.
What I want is none of your business.
ما أريده ليس من شأنك.
Nongyu,
نونجيو،
don't be fooled by him.
لا تنخدع به.
Only I can help you.
أنا فقط من يمكنه مساعدتك.
Li Ling and I appreciate each other
أنا ولي لينغ نقدر بعضنا البعض
and are in love.
وهم في حالة حب.
This is my choice.
هذا هو اختياري.
Fine.
بخير.
Since things have come to this,
منذ أن وصلت الأمور إلى هذا،
I won't be polite anymore.
لن أكون مهذبا بعد الآن.
Today, between you two,
اليوم بينكما
only one can leave this place.
لا يمكن لأحد سوى شخص واحد مغادرة هذا المكان.
As for who it will be...
وأما من سيكون...
You decide.
أنت تقرر.
Then I'll give you two choices as well.
ثم سأعطيك خيارين أيضًا.
Either kneel and beg for mercy,
إما أن تركع وتتوسل الرحمة،
or...
أو...
have your head separated from your body.
افصل رأسك عن جسدك.
Yu Linxun.
يو لينشون.
That sword in his hand,
هذا السيف في يده،
is it your father's?
هل هو لوالدك؟
Indeed, it's my father's treasured sword.
إنه في الواقع سيف والدي الثمين.
Then he couldn't possibly know
ثم لا يمكنه أن يعرف
who killed your father back then.
من الذي قتل والدك في ذلك الوقت؟
I heard in the army
سمعت في الجيش
that General Feng's treasured sword
هذا السيف الثمين للجنرال فنغ
was unfortunately lost during the battle of Tongguan.
لقد فقدت للأسف خلال معركة تونغجوان.
Later when I joined the Chen household,
وفي وقت لاحق عندما انضممت إلى أسرة تشين،
I saw Chen Jingbian playing with it.
رأيت تشين جينغبيان يلعب بها.
If I'm not mistaken,
إذا لم أكن مخطئا،
you must have bought it from Chen Jingbian.
لا بد أنك اشتريته من تشين جينغبيان.
So there's no way you could know
لذلك لا توجد طريقة لمعرفة ذلك
the truth about what happened back then.
الحقيقة حول ما حدث في ذلك الوقت.
Master Chen, please.
سيد تشين، من فضلك.
Come.
يأتي.
But you used this
ولكنك استخدمت هذا
to deceive Yin Niang
لخداع يين نيانغ
to make her serve him
لتجعلها تخدمه
and be used by him.
وأن يستخدمه.
Am I right?
هل انا على حق؟
Is what he's saying true?
هل ما يقوله صحيح؟
It is true.
هذا صحيح.
The sword?
السيف؟
I did buy it from Chen Jingbian
لقد اشتريته من تشين جينغبيان
and paid quite a sum for it.
ودفعت مبلغًا كبيرًا مقابل ذلك.
But I wasn't lying.
ولكنني لم أكن أكذب.
Once you get the Firefly Map
بمجرد حصولك على خريطة Firefly
I'll naturally know everything.
سأعرف كل شيء بطبيعة الحال.
It surely contains records
فهو بالتأكيد يحتوي على سجلات
about what your father did back then.
عما فعله والدك في ذلك الوقت.
I'll definitely tell you everything.
سأخبرك بكل شيء بالتأكيد.
Su Changming, you bastard!
سو تشانغمينغ، أيها الوغد!
Return the sword to Nongyu.
إرجاع السيف إلى نونغيو.
I never said I wouldn't return it.
لم أقل أبدًا أنني لن أرجعه.
I offered it to you before,
لقد عرضتها عليك من قبل،
but you refused to take it.
ولكنك رفضت أن تأخذه.
Fine.
بخير.
No more arguing.
لا مزيد من الجدال.
Here you go.
ها أنت ذا.
Take it.
خذها.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Wait.
انتظر.
I've given everything back,
لقد أعطيت كل شيء مرة أخرى،
so at least let me say something.
لذا دعني أقول شيئًا على الأقل.
I want to make a bet with you.
أريد الرهان معك.
Today you're taking both the person and the sword,
اليوم تأخذ الشخص والسيف معًا،
but I dare say
ولكنني أجرؤ على القول
before long
قبل فترة طويلة
you'll bring both the person and the sword
سوف تحضر الشخص والسيف معًا
back to me yourself.
عد إلي بنفسك.
In your dreams!
في أحلامك!
Loser dies.
الخاسر يموت.
Fine.
بخير.
I'll take that bet.
سأقبل هذا الرهان.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Young Master,
السيد الشاب،
are you just letting them leave like this?
هل تسمح لهم بالمغادرة بهذه الطريقة؟
Yes, indeed.
نعم بالفعل.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
This is just the beginning.
هذه مجرد البداية.
The best is yet to come.
الأفضل لم يأت بعد.
Do you want to take a break?
هل تريد أن تأخذ استراحة؟
We're about to enter the city.
نحن على وشك الدخول إلى المدينة.
Why don't we go back to Tongxin Quarter first
لماذا لا نعود إلى حي تونغشين أولاً؟
and place the jade dagger at General Feng's memorial?
ووضع خنجر اليشم في النصب التذكاري للجنرال فينج؟
By the way.
بالمناسبة.
You mentioned seeing this dagger
لقد ذكرت أنك رأيت هذا الخنجر
when you were with Chen Jingbian.
عندما كنت مع تشين جينغبيان.
Do you know where this dagger came from?
هل تعلم من أين جاء هذا الخنجر؟
I don't know the details.
لا أعرف التفاصيل.
I only heard from Yu Yaonou that
لقد سمعت فقط من يو ياونو أن
this dagger was probably given
ربما تم إهداء هذا الخنجر
to Chen Jingbian by An Lushan.
لتشن جينغبيان بواسطة آن لوشان.
I believe
انا أؤمن
it must have fallen into the hands of the Great Yan army
لا بد أنها سقطت في أيدي جيش يان العظيم
after the defeat at Tongguan.
بعد الهزيمة في تونغجوان.
That old eunuch dog,
ذلك الكلب الخصي العجوز،
how dare he!
كيف يجرؤ!
If I find out
إذا اكتشفت
he had anything to do with what happened,
كان له أي علاقة بما حدث،
I'll tear him to pieces.
سأمزقه إلى قطع.
Nongyu.
نونجيو.
Miss Yin.
السيدة يين.
I believe
انا أؤمن
General Feng
الجنرال فنغ
would never betray his country.
لن يخون بلاده أبدًا.
Someone must have framed him.
لا بد أن يكون شخص ما قد أوقع به في الفخ.
Rest assured,
اطمئن، لا تشغل بالك،
I will find the real culprit.
سأجد الجاني الحقيقي.
I will clear the names
سأمسح الأسماء
of General Feng
للجنرال فنغ
and your entire family.
وعائلتك بأكملها.
Li Ling.
لي لينغ.
The criminal Feng Jianye.
المجرم فنغ جياني.
Defied imperial orders
تحدى الأوامر الإمبراطورية
and resisted passively.
وقاومت بشكل سلبي.
Colluded with the enemy and betrayed the country.
تواطأ مع العدو وخان البلاد.
Attempted to obstruct the imperial mission
حاول عرقلة المهمة الإمبراطورية
and plotted to overthrow the state.
وتآمروا لإسقاط الدولة.
He must be eliminated
يجب القضاء عليه
without mercy.
بدون رحمة.
That's not true.
هذا ليس صحيحا.
The general and I fought desperately on the battlefield.
لقد قاتلت أنا والجنرال بشكل يائس في ساحة المعركة.
How could he possibly betray his country?
كيف يمكنه أن يخون بلاده؟
Sir.
سيد.
I am the general's deputy commander.
أنا نائب القائد العام.
We have been here all this time.
لقد كنا هنا كل هذا الوقت.
I know the truth.
انا اعرف الحقيقة
The truth is not like this.
الحقيقة ليست كذلك.
Li Ling.
لي لينغ.
Silence! Don't say another word.
صمت! لا تقل كلمة أخرى.
General.
عام.
Stop talking.
توقف عن الكلام.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
You're just a minor officer.
أنت مجرد ضابط صغير.
How dare you defy the Emperor's will!
كيف تجرؤ على تحدي إرادة الإمبراطور!
And you, Feng Jianye.
وأنت، فنغ جياني.
Allowing your subordinate to disobey imperial orders.
السماح لمرؤوسيك بمخالفة الأوامر الإمبراطورية.
Do you know what punishment you deserve?
هل تعرف ما هو العقاب الذي تستحقه؟
Please calm down, sir.
من فضلك اهدأ يا سيدي.
A soldier's duty is to obey orders.
واجب الجندي هو طاعة الأوامر.
Both punishment and favor come from His Majesty's grace.
إن العقاب والنعمة تأتيان من نعمة جلالته.
I, Feng Jianye, accept the imperial decree.
أنا، فينج جيانيي، قبلت المرسوم الإمبراطوري.
But I also believe...
ولكنني أعتقد أيضًا...
Heaven's principles are clear.
مبادئ السماء واضحة.
Right and wrong...
الصواب والخطأ...
His Majesty will be just.
جلالته سيكون عادلا.
General.
عام.
Leave.
يترك.
That's an order.
هذا أمر.
General.
عام.
Get up.
استيقظ.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
General.
عام.
Move.
يتحرك.
Father,
أب،
don't worry.
لا تقلق.
When Chang'an is liberated,
عندما تم تحرير تشانغآن،
I will surely engrave your name on it.
سأنقش اسمك عليه بالتأكيد.
Master Chen, please have a look.
سيد تشين، من فضلك ألقي نظرة.
This is Feng Jianye's priceless treasure,
هذا هو كنز فينج جيانيي الذي لا يقدر بثمن،
the Yu Linxun sword.
سيف يو لينكشون.
Indeed, it's a blade sharp enough to split a hair.
إنها في الواقع شفرة حادة بما يكفي لتقسيم الشعرة.
Sir,
سيد،
An Lushan's envoy has arrived.
لقد وصل مبعوث آن لوشان.
This great victory at Tongguan Pass
هذا النصر العظيم في ممر تونغجوان
is all thanks to General Chen's brilliant strategy.
كل هذا بفضل الاستراتيجية الرائعة للجنرال تشين.
His Majesty praises you as Great Yan's fortunate general.
جلالته يشيد بك باعتبارك الجنرال المحظوظ ليان العظيم.
And the Night Firefly Map in your possession
وخريطة Night Firefly في حوزتك
was the key to our victory.
كان مفتاح انتصارنا.
To be recognized by Emperor Xiongwu
ليتم التعرف عليه من قبل الإمبراطور شيونغوو
is my great fortune.
هذه هي ثروتي العظيمة.
For the grand ambitions of Great Yan,
من أجل الطموحات الكبرى ليان العظيم،
I am willing to sacrifice everything,
أنا مستعد للتضحية بكل شيء،
whatever it takes.
مهما كان الأمر.
Good.
جيد.
What about Feng Jianye?
ماذا عن فنغ جياني؟
That stubborn fellow.
هذا الرجل العنيد.
I tried to persuade him for hours,
حاولت إقناعه لساعات،
but he absolutely refuses to surrender.
لكنّه يرفض الاستسلام تمامًا.
If he cannot serve us,
إذا لم يستطع أن يخدمنا،
then we must eliminate any future threat.
ومن ثم يتعين علينا القضاء على أي تهديد مستقبلي.
Rest assured, Envoy.
اطمئن يا مبعوث.
I've made arrangements.
لقد اتخذت الترتيبات.
Today, Feng Jianye will attempt to escape prison and fail,
اليوم، سيحاول فينج جياني الهروب من السجن ويفشل،
dying under a hail of blades.
الموت تحت وابل من الشفرات.
General Feng,
الجنرال فنغ،
we're sorry,
آسفون،
but we're here to end your life.
ولكننا هنا لإنهاء حياتك.
General!
عام!
General.
عام.
Chen Jingbian, you treacherous dog!
تشن جينغبيان، أيها الكلب الغادر!
Chen Jingbian.
تشن جينغبيان.
We can't return to Chang'an anymore.
لم يعد بإمكاننا العودة إلى تشانغآن بعد الآن.
We can go to Western Shu.
يمكننا أن نذهب إلى غرب شو.
We'll find the Emperor there
سوف نجد الإمبراطور هناك
and seek justice from him.
وطلب العدالة منه.
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
My life doesn't matter,
حياتي لا تهم
but the foundation of our great Tang
لكن أساس تانغ العظيم لدينا
must never fall into enemy hands.
لا ينبغي أن تقع في أيدي العدو أبدًا.
Now the Emperor has fled west,
الآن فر الإمبراطور غربًا،
Chen Jingbian has surrendered Chang'an,
لقد استسلم تشين جينجبيان تشانغآن،
and half of our Tang territory
ونصف أراضي تانغ لدينا
has already fallen apart.
لقد انهارت بالفعل.
As long as the traitors remain,
ما دام الخونة باقين
the war will continue.
الحرب سوف تستمر
Weapons will clash everywhere,
ستشتبك الأسلحة في كل مكان،
people will suffer,
الناس سوف يعانون
and civilians will have no way to survive.
ولن يكون لدى المدنيين أي وسيلة للبقاء على قيد الحياة.
General,
عام،
we need to heal you first.
نحن بحاجة إلى شفائك أولاً.
I've long known
لقد عرفت منذ زمن طويل
that Chen Jingbian, that villain,
هذا تشين جينغبيان، هذا الشرير،
would become a great threat.
سيصبح تهديدًا كبيرًا.
Li Ling.
لي لينغ.
You must find a way
يجب عليك أن تجد طريقة
to get the Night Firefly Map from him.
للحصول على خريطة Night Firefly منه.
General!
عام!
It's crucial
إنه أمر بالغ الأهمية
for our Tang's future victory.
من أجل انتصار تانغ المستقبلي.
General,
عام،
it's too late.
لقد فات الأوان.
I don't have much time left.
لم يتبق لي الكثير من الوقت.
No, that's not true.
لا، هذا ليس صحيحا.
Do you remember
هل تذكر
what I told you that day
ما قلته لك في ذلك اليوم
when you touched the jade carving?
عندما لمست نحت اليشم؟
The person you become
الشخص الذي تصبح عليه
is not determined by your birth,
لا يتم تحديده من خلال ميلادك،
but is held
ولكن يتم عقده
in your own hands.
بين يديك.
General...
عام...
You... use your hands
أنت... تستخدم يديك
to build your own achievements.
لبناء إنجازاتك الخاصة.
You are the best soldier
أنت أفضل جندي
I've ever trained.
لقد تدربت من قبل.
General!
عام!
Take my head to Chen Jingbian.
خذ رأسي إلى تشين جينغبيان.
He's naturally suspicious.
إنه مشبوه بطبيعته.
Only this way
فقط بهذه الطريقة
can you infiltrate and get the map.
هل يمكنك التسلل والحصول على الخريطة؟
I won't.
أنا لن.
I can't.
لا أستطبع.
Do it.
افعلها.
Li Ling,
لي لينغ,
do it now!
افعلها الآن!
No!
لا!
This is a military order!
هذا أمر عسكري!
Do it now!
افعلها الآن!
Er
يكون
Xie Zheng
شيه تشنغ
Xiaoke
شياوكي
Kang Sun Wang
كانغ سون وانغ
Ying
ينغ
Tu Lin Tu
تو لين تو
Tong Liu
تونغ ليو
Hao Xiao
هاو شياو
Li Li Zhang
لي لي تشانغ
Zhang
تشانغ
Yu Jia
يو جيا
Jia Ning Tao Jia
جيا نينغ تاو جيا
Jia Ning Tao Jia Ying Xi Dou Rong
جيا نينغ تاو جيا ينغ شي دو رونغ
Jia Ning Tao Jia Ying Xi Dou Rong Jing Shou Peng
جيا نينغ تاو جيا ينغ شي دو رونغ جينغ شو بنغ
Li
الذي - التي
Assistant Li
المساعد لي
Li Sheng Lan
لي لي شنغ لان
Li Sheng Lan Feng Tao
لي شنغ لان فنغ تاو
Sheng Lan Feng Tao
شينغ لان فنغ تاو
Limited Company
شركة محدودة